One thing you might have noticed is that in a single line of Python,
你可能注意到了一点 在一行 Python 代码中
whitespace doesn't really affect how your code works.
空格并不会影响到代码的运行效果
For example, this will give exactly the same output as this, however.
例如 这行代码和这行代码的输出完全一样
That doesn't mean that these lines are equally good lines of code.
但是 这并不表示这行代码是同样很好的代码
Learning how to write clear and readable code is
学习如何编写易于读懂的清晰代码
critical for others in your company and future you to understand.
对公司内的其他同事以及日后阅读来说非常重要
Here are some best practices for code style in Python.
下面介绍下 Python 中的代码样式最佳做法
When you call a function like print,
在调用 print 等函数时
put the opening parentheses straight after the name of the function,
将左括号直接放在函数名称之后
like here. Not like this.
就像这样 而不是这样
Don't put extra spaces immediately inside the parentheses either.
也不要在括号后面加上多余的空格
So, this is good. But this isn't.
这个很好 这个不行
If you are mixing operators with
如果使用了多种运算符并且优先级不同
different priorities like multiplication and subtraction,
例如乘法和减法
then you might like to add a space around the lower priority,
则需要在优先级低的运算符周围加上空格
in this case subtraction,
这里是减号周围
to make the code easier to read.
使代码更容易阅读
See how this is slightly harder to comprehend for operation order.
这样不太容易看出运算顺序
Don't write extremely long lines of code.
一行代码不要太长
They're hard to understand.
这样很难看懂
People commonly limit themselves to lines that are 79 or 99 characters long.
人们通常能读懂一行有 79 - 99 个字符的代码
If you feel like you need to write longer lines,
如果你觉得一行需要更长
consider rewriting, simplifying, or separating your code into multiple lines.
则考虑重新编写 简化或将代码分成多行
These conventions come from the Python developers guide,
这些规范摘自 Python 开发者指南
which has a style guide called PEP 8, which is linked below.
有一个叫做 PEP 8 的样式指南 下面给出了链接
There's a lot in there.
其中列出了很多条目
Don't worry, you don't need to digest it all now.
别担心 你不需要立即理解所有内容
Why are these conventions important?
这些规范为何很重要？
Although how you format the code doesn't affect how it runs,
虽然代码格式不会影响到代码的运行
following standard style guidelines makes code
但是遵守标准样式指南使代码更容易读懂
easier to read and consistent among different developers on a team.
并且在团队内的多个开发者之间保持一致性
So, it's a good idea to follow the guidelines,
因此建议你遵守这些指南
even with one line expressions.
即使只是一行代码
It will be useful to refer back to PEP 8 once in a while to get your Python style right.
建议偶尔参考下 PEP 8 以便采用正确的 Python 样式
Later, we'll also learn about tools that can check your code for you,
稍后 我们将学习根据 PEP 8 指南
and provide suggestions based on PEP 8 guidelines.
帮助检查代码并提供建议的工具